星际迷航06: 迈入未来
Stardate 9521.6.
星历9521.6
Captain's log U.S.S. Excelsior. Hikaru Sulu commanding.
船长日志 上进号由苏路指挥
After three years I've concluded my first assignment as master of this vessel
我首次完成叁年的船长任务
cataloguing gaseous planetary anomalies in Beta Quadrant.
记载第二区的气体反常现象
We're heading home under full impulse power.
我们正全速返回基地
I'm pleased to report that ship and crew have functioned well.
太空船和船员一切正常
According to this,we've completed our survey of the entire sector.
我们己完成全区的调查工作
I have an energy wave at 240 degrees mark six port.
这里有强度240的能量流
Visual!
看
My... God!
天
Shields. Shields!
快开防护罩
She's not answering her helm.
太空船没有反应
Starboard thrusters. Turn her into the wave.
右边推进器 转入气流中
Go to impulse power.
撞击力真大
Damage report. Checking all systems.
损毁报告 检查所有系统
That was no meteor shower. Negative,sir.
不是有流星雨吧 不是
The sub-space shock-wave originated at bearing 323.75.
子空间震动来自323.75方位
Location... It's Praxis,sir. It's a Klingon moon.
位置是普拉西斯 克林冈卫星
Praxis is their key energy production facility.
那是他们主要的能源产地
Send to Klingon High Command. 'This is Excelsior,a Federation Starship.'
发讯给克林冈指挥部说我们是星盟
'We have monitored a large explosion in your sector.'
测出他们区内发生大爆炸
'Do you require assistance?' Aye,sir.
问他们是否需要援助 知道
Mr Vultane,any more data? I've confirmed Praxis' location,but...
有其他资料吗？我确定了它的位置 但…
I cannot confirm Praxis' existence. On screen.
无法确定它的存在 放出来看
Magnify. Computer enhancement.
放大
Praxis? What's left of it,sir.
这就是普拉西斯？对
Captain,I'm getting a message from Praxis.
我收到普拉西斯的讯息
Let's have it.
接过来
This is Brigadier Kerla, speaking for the High Command.
我是卡拉 指挥部发言人
There has been an incident on Praxis.
普拉西斯的确有事发生
However,everything is under control. We have no need for assistance.
但一切己恢复正常 不需援助
Obey treaty stipulations and remain outside the Neutral Zone.
遵守条约规定 别进入中立区
This transmission ends now.
通讯完毕
An incident? Do we report this,sir?
有事发生？我们要报告此事吗？
Are you kidding?
笑话
舰队总部
What are we doing here? Maybe it's a retirement party.
我们为什麽要来？可能是退休派对
That suits me. I just bought a boat.
真好 我刚买了小船
I'm supposed to be chairing a seminar at the Academy.
我本来要开学术会议
Isn't this just for top brass? Where is Sulu?
这是高层人员会议吗 苏路呢？
Captain Sulu? On assignment. Where's Spock?
苏路有任务在身 那 史波克 呢？
This briefing is classified. Ladies and gentlemen,the C-in-C.
这次议程要保密 有请总司令
As you were.
请坐
I'll break this information down succinctly.
让我简述一下
The Klingon empire has 50 years of life left.
克林冈帝国只剩下五十年寿命
For full details,I'm turning this briefing over to the Federation Special Envoy.
详细情况由星盟特使交代
Good morning.
大家早
Two months ago a Federation Starship monitored an explosion on Praxis.
我们两个月前测出普拉西斯发生爆炸
We believe it was caused by over-mining and insufficient safety precautions.
可能因为采矿过度及安全设施不足
The moon's decimation means a deadly pollution of their ozone.
卫星爆炸导致臭氧层严重污染
They will have depleted their oxygen supply in 50 Earth years.
他们的氧气在五十年内就会耗尽
Due to their enormous military budget
由於军事开支太大
the Klingon economy doesn't have the resources to combat this catastrophe.
克林冈人没有经济能力应付这场灾难
Last month,at the behest of the Vulcan Ambassador,
上月 应维冈总理要求
I opened a dialogue with Gorkon, Chancellor of the Klingon High Council.
我与克林冈总理高冈对话
He proposes to commence negotiations at once.
他建议马上展开谈判
Negotiations for what?
谈什麽？
The dismantling of our space stations and bases along the Neutral Zone.
解散中立区的太空站
An end to 70 years of hostility, which the Klingons can no longer afford.
结束七十年敌对状态
Bill,are we talking about mothballing the Starfleet?
我们要星际舰队作後备？
Our exploration and scientific programs would be unaffected,but...
这不影响我们的科学探测计划
I must protest!
我一定反对
To offer Klingons safe haven within Federation space is suicide.
在星盟范围内庇护克林冈人等於自杀
Klingons would become the alien trash of the galaxy.
他们会变成银河系的外星垃圾
If we dismantle the fleet,
如果解散舰队
we'd be defenceless before an aggressive species on our territory.
我们就无力对抗敌人
The opportunity here is to bring them to their knees.
我们一定要使他们屈服
Then we'll be in a better position to dictate terms.
才能发号施令
Sir... Captain Kirk?
长官却克船长？
The Klingons have never been trustworthy.
克林冈人从不可靠
I agree with Admiral Cartwright. This is a terrifying idea.
我同意卡上将的观点这个做法太恐布了
It is imperative that we act now to support the Gorkon initiative,
当前急务是要支持高冈
lest more conservative elements persuade his empire
免得克林冈的保守势力…
that it's better to attempt a military solution and die fighting.
煽动战争
You,Captain Kirk, are to be our first olive branch.
却克船长 你是首个和平大使
We are to rendezvous with the vessel which is bringing Gorkon to Earth
我们要会合高冈的太空船
and to escort him safely through Federation space.
全程安全护送他
Me?
我？
There are Klingons who feel the same about the peace treaty as yourself,
你和克林冈人对和约有同感
but they'll think twice about attacking the Enterprise under your command.
有你指挥他们不会轻易攻击企业号
I have personally vouched for you in this matter.
我私人担保你负责这项任务
You have personally vouched...?
你私人担保？
You will extend Chancellor Gorkon full diplomatic courtesy,Captain.
你要以十足外交礼节款待高冈
A full Ambassador is better equipped... If there's no further business...
我要有经验的大使 没有其他问题的话
I wish you and your crew Godspeed. Thank you,ladies and gentlemen.
我预祝你成功 散会
I remind you this meeting is classified.
紧记这个会议要保密
I don't know whether to congratulate you or not,Jim.
我不知应否恭喜你
I wouldn't.
我不会恭喜你
We volunteered?
我们是自愿的？
There's an old Vulcan proverb. 'Only Nixon could go to China.'
维冈人有句俗语 尼克逊才可到中国去
How could you vouch for me?
你怎能担保我？
That's arrogant presumption. My father requested that I open...
那是我自作主张 我父亲要求我展开谈判
I know your father is the Vulcan Ambassador,but you know how I feel.
我知道你父亲是维冈大使但你知道我的感受吗？
They're animals. Jim...
他们是野兽 却克
There is an historic opportunity here. Don't believe them! Don't trust them.
这是难得的机会 别相信他们
They're dying. Let them die.
他们快死了 让他们自生自灭
Has it occurred to you that this crew is due to stand down in three months?
舰队叁个月内就要解散了
We've done our bit for king and country.
我们一直为此而努力
You should have trusted me.
你该相信我
Control,this is S-D 103, approach to Space dock. Over.
控制台 这是S D103接近太空码头
You are clear to deliver Captain Kirk and party to N.C.C. 1701 Alpha.
接却克船长及队员到NCC1701
Captain on the bridge! As you were. Lieutenant...?
船长到了你是少校…
Val'eris,sir. We were told you needed a helmsman,so I volunteered.
韦利丽 我自荐做舵手的
It is agreeable to see you again.
很高兴再见到你
She was the first Vulcan to graduate at the top of her class at the Academy.
她是首个维冈人高材生
You must be very proud. I don't believe so,sir.
你一定很自豪 不是
She's a Vulcan,alright.
她是维冈人
Let's get this over with. Departure stations.
我们开始吧 离境站
Scotty? Did you find the engine room? Right where I left it.
史葛 找到引擎室吗？找到了
Stand by. Uhura,get me the dock master.
准备 乌娜 替我接码头职员
Control tower reading,sir.
控制台读数
Control,this is Enterprise requesting permission to depart.
控制台 企业号申请离境
This is Control. Permission to depart granted. 30 seconds for port gates.
申请获接纳 离闸门有叁十秒
Clear all moorings. Awaiting port gates from this mark.
清除船索在此等候
All lines clear. Aft thrusters.
船索清除了後推进器
Thank you,Lieutenant. 1 quarter impulse power.
谢谢 要1/4动力
Captain,regulations specify thrusters only while in space dock.
船长 推进器只限在码头上用
Jim...
却克…
You heard the order,Lieutenant.
按指示做
Aye,sir.
知道
Captain's log. Stardate 9522.6.
船长日志 星历98522.6
I've never trusted Klingons, and I never will.
我从不信任克林冈人
I can never forgive them for the death of my boy.
他们害死我儿子 不能原谅
To escort the Chancellor of the Klingon High Council to a peace summit
护送克林冈总理到和平高峰会
is problematic,at best.
真是棘手的工作
Spock says this could be an historic occasion. I'd like to believe him.
史波克 说这是历史性时刻希望他对吧
But how on Earth can history get past people like me?
但我怎能担当这历史重任？
Sorry. You could have knocked.
对不起你该敲门
We are almost at the rendezvous,sir. I thought that you would like to know.
快到会合处了 我特来报告
Permission to speak freely,sir. It is an honour to serve with you.
船长 我很荣幸能为你效劳
You piloted well out of space dock, Lieutenant.
你的太空驾驶技术不错
I've always wanted to try that.
这是我的志愿
You've done well,Val'eris.
做得好
As your sponsor at the Academy I've followed your career with satisfaction.
我对你的工作表现很满意
And as a Vulcan, you have exceeded my expectations.
你比我预期中还出色
I do not understand this representation.
这幅画代表什麽？
It's a depiction from ancient Earth mythology.
是古时地球传说的描绘
'The expulsion from Paradise.'
被逐出天堂
Why keep it in your quarters? To remind me that all things end.
为什麽要挂在房里？提醒自己一切也会完
It is of endings that I wish to speak.
我很想说出这个结局
Sir,I address you as a kindred intellect.
我视你为我们族中的智者
Do you not recognise...
你察觉到…
that a turning point has been reached in the affairs of the Federation?
星盟出现转捩点吗？
History is replete with turning points. You must have faith.
历史充满转捩点 怀着信心
Faith? The universe will unfold as it should.
信心？宇宙正在发展
Is that logical? Surely we must... Logic,logic,logic.
合逻辑吗？我们肯定… 合逻辑…
Logic is the beginning of wisdom, Val'eris. Not the end.
逻辑是智慧之始 不是终结
This will be my final voyage on board this vessel as a member of her crew.
这是我最後一次乘太空船
Nature abhors a vacuum.
位置不能空着
I intend you to replace me.
我想由你继任
I could only succeed you,sir.
我会好好接替你的工作
Now hear this. All officers to the bridge.
所有人员请到驾驶台
Klingon battle cruiser off the port bow. All Officers to the bridge.
克林冈巡航机离开了码头所有人员请到驾驶台
Captain on the bridge!
船长到了
Shall we raise our shields,Captain?
要开防护罩吗？
I've never been this close.
从未如此接近过
The Chancellor is undoubtedly awaiting our signal.
总理在等候指示
Uhura,hailing frequencies. Aye,sir.
乌娜 打信号招呼 知道
Right standard rudder. Bring us alongside.
用右舵靠过去
Right standard rudder. Z plus 5 degrees.
右舵z加5度
Channel is open,Captain.
接通了
This is the Starship Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk commanding.
这是企业号太空船由却克船长指挥
This is Kronos One. I am Chancellor Gorkon.
这是卡龙诺斯一号我是高冈总理
We've been ordered to escort you to your meeting on Earth.
我们奉命护送你到地球开会
Thank you.
谢谢
Would you and your party care to dine this evening aboard the Enterprise
你们想来企业号进晚餐吗？
as guests of the United Federation of Planets?
来星盟作客好吗？
We would be delighted to accept your gracious invitation.
我们乐意接受邀请
We'll make arrangements to have you beamed aboard at 19:30 hours.
我们七点半安排你们上船
I shall look forward to that.
我热切期待
I hope you're happy.
你满意了吧
Captain! There is a supply of Romulan ale aboard.
船长 我们有麦芽酒
It might make the evening pass more... smoothly.
有助聚会顺利进行
Officer thinking,Lieutenant.
好主意
Guess who's coming to dinner.
你猜谁会来？
Energize.
通电
Chancellor Gorkon. Captain Kirk.
高冈总理切克船长
May I present Captain Spock, whom I believe you know.
这是 史波克 你见过的
Captain,face to face at last. You have my thanks.
我们终於见面了 谢谢你
Chancellor.
总理
Gentlemen.
各位
This is my daughter,Azetbur...
这是我的女儿阿惜宝
My military advisor,Brigadier Kerla...
我的军事顾问卡拉
and this is General Chang, my chief of staff.
这是总参谋长张上将
I have so wanted to meet you,Captain.
久仰大名
I'm not sure how to take that. Sincere admiration,Kirk.
过奖了 他真的很仰慕你
From one warrior to another.
战士之间的感情
Right...
对
This way. You might enjoy a brief tour.
请来这边参观一下
They all look alike. What about that smell?
他们的长相全都差不多 还有那股气味
You know only top of the line models can even talk...
只有首领才能说话
You men have work? Yes,ma'am.
你们有工作做吗？有
Then snap to it.
快去办事
I offer a toast.
齐来乾杯
The undiscovered country.
为尚未发现的地方
The future. The undiscovered country.
为未来为尚未发现的地方
Hamlet,act 3,scene 1.
哈姆雷特第叁幕第一场
You have not experienced Shakespeare until you've read him in Klingon.
看过克林冈文的莎士比亚才知道个中乐趣
Captain Kirk. I thought Romulan ale was illegal.
麦芽酒不是非法的吗？
An advantage of being 1,000 light years from Federation headquarters.
离星盟总部还有一千光年没有问题
To you,Chancellor Gorkon. One of the architects of our future.
敬高冈总理一杯他是我们未来的栋梁
Chancellor!
为总理乾杯
Perhaps we are looking at something of that future here.
可能我们现在己看到未来
Tell me,Captain Kirk. Would you be willing to give up Starfleet?
却克 你愿放弃星际舰队吗？
The Captain feels that Starfleet's mission has always been one of peace.
船长认为舰队做的是和平任务
I wouldn't dispute my first officer. Starfleet has always been...
我没有异议 舰队一向…
There's no need to mince words. In space,all warriors are cold warriors.
不用转弯抹角太空所有战士也很冷酷
General, are you fond of... Shakespeare?
你喜欢莎士比亚吗？
We believe all planets have a sovereign claim to inalienable human rights.
我们认为所有星球也该争取不可剥夺的人权
'Inalien...' If you could only hear yourselves.
不可剥夺 你们只听取己见
'Human rights.' Why,the very name is racist.
人权一词有种族歧视之意
The Federation is a 'homo sapiens only' club.
星盟不再是智人的专利
Present company excepted,of course.
现时的同伴除外
We know where this is leading the annihilation of our culture.
我们的文化会因此毁灭
That's not true. No!
不对…
'To be or not to be'...That is the question which preoccupies our people.
做与不做是困扰我们的问题
We need breathing room. Earth. Hitler,1938.
我们需要呼吸空间 地球 希特拉 1938年
I beg your pardon?
你说什麽？
Well...
好了…
I see we have a long way to go.
我们要走的路还漫长
We must do this again sometime.
欢迎下次再来
You don't trust me,do you? I don't blame you.
你不相信我？我不怪你
If there is to be a brave new world,
如果有新的世界
our generation is going to have the hardest time living in it.
我们的生活会十分艰难
Captain Spock. Chancellor. Madam.
洗 总理 小姐
Captain.
船长
Well,most kind.
谢谢款待
Parting is such sweet sorrow. Hmm,Captain?
分离真是甜蜜的悲痛
'Have we not heard the chimes at midnight? '
听到午夜的报时钟吗？
Thank God!
谢天谢地
Did you see the way they ate? Terrible table manners.
看到他们的食相吗？全无餐桌礼仪可言
I doubt our own behaviour will distinguish us in the annals of diplomacy.
我们在外交史上一定很出众
I'm going to sleep this off. Is there any other way we can screw up tonight?
我要睡了 今晚真是一团糟
I'm going to go find a pot of black coffee.
我要喝咖啡
The Enterprise hosted Chancellor Gorkon to dinner last night.
高冈总理昨晚到企业号进晚餐
Our manners weren't exactly Emily Post.
我们的态度不太合礼节
To the galley Romulan ale no longer to be served at diplomatic functions.
通知厨房:以後的外交场合不得端上麦芽酒
Captain Kirk,will you please join me on the bridge? Captain Kirk?
却克 请到驾驶台找我
Captain. What is it?
船长有什麽事？
I find this curious. Spock,I'm really tired.
我感到奇怪我很累
We are reading an enormous amount of neutron radiation.
我们录得大量中子辐射
Where? It appears to emanate from us.
在哪里？好像由我们发射
The Enterprise?
企业号？
Val'eris,do you know anything about a radiation surge? Chekov?
韦利丽 你知道辐射激增吗？查哥夫 你呢？
Only the size of my head.
只有我的头那麽大
I know what you mean.
我明白了
What's happened? We've fired on the Chancellor's ship.
发生什麽事？我们射中了总理的船
Torpedo room! Please confirm,have we fired?
发射室 我们有否发炮？
Uhura,monitor. Aye,sir.
乌娜 监测一下 知道
Direct hit. Confirmed,sir.
直接击中证实了
我们失去引力
我们被出卖了
This is the bridge. Do you read me?
这是驾驶台 收到吗？
Did we fire those torpedoes? Negative. We're still fully loaded.
我们有否发炮？没有 炸弹没消耗
找张上将
Unable to confirm or deny firing the torpedoes.
无法确定有否发炮
Hailing frequencies. Aye,sir.
打信号招呼 知道
Kronos One,this is Enterprise. Do you read?
卡龙诺斯一号这是企业号 收到吗？
It's very hard to make out. There's been weapons firing and a lot of shouting.
情况混乱 有枪声和尖叫声
She's still listing. She's spinning out of control.
船倾斜了 它失控地转
恢复後备引力
Have you not a shred of decency in you,Kirk?
你一点气量也没有
We come in peace, and you blatantly defy that peace.
你违背了我们的和约
For that, I shall blow you out of the stars.
我要你在宇宙中消失
We haven't fired. Captain...
我们没有发炮 船长…
According to our data banks, we have. Twice...
资料库显示我们发了两炮
Captain,they're coming about.
船长 他们来了
They're preparing to fire. Shields up,Captain?
他们准备开火要开防护罩吗？
Captain,our shields. Shields up,Captain?
防护罩要开骂？
Signal our surrender.
发投降信号
We surrender!
我们投降
This is Enterprise. We surrender. If they fire,with our shields down...
企业号宣布投降 若他们发炮 我们没防护罩
we will not be able to respond. Repeat,Enterprise surrenders.
我们毫无还击之力 重复 企业号投降
Are we firing torpedoes? I wish I knew.
我们有发炮吗？我也想知道
I'm going aboard. Spock,take the con. I involved you,I will go.
我要上船 你在此控制 我该负责 让我去吧
No,I'll go. We'll not be the instigators of war on the eve of universal peace.
我去 总不能在和谈前夕开战
I'm going too,they may need a doctor.
我也去 他们需要医生
Uhura,tell them we're coming, and tell them we're unarmed.
乌娜 通知他们我们要上船 没有带武器
Have you lost your mind? ! I don't understand what's happened.
你疯了吗？我也不知发生什麽事
We're here to help.
我们来帮忙的
Follow me.
跟我来
Chancellor Gorkon. My God! What has happened here?
高冈总理 天 发生什麽事？
You dare to feign ignorance? What happened?
你还装作无知？他怎麽了？
With a direct torpedo hit, you crippled our gravitational field
被直接击中你破坏我们的引力系统
and two of your Starfleet crew beamed aboard wearing magnetic boots.
你们派来的凶手穿了磁靴
Aren't you carrying a surgeon? We were until this disgrace.
你们有医生吗？我们差不多全军覆没
Then for God's sake,let me help.
让我为他急救
I've got a pulse we can move him. I need light. Put him on the table.
他还有脉搏 来 搬他到桌上
Hold him! Hold him while I stabilize him.
捉紧他 我要稳定他的情况
I said hold him!
捉紧他
Sweet Jesus.
天
Can you...? I don't even know his anatomy.
你行吗？我不清楚他的构造
His wounds are not closing. He's killing him!
他的伤口不愈合 他想杀他
He's gone into some kind of damned arrest.
他的身体机能停滞了
Come on,dammit! Come on!
醒醒 醒来
He's not responding.
他没有反应
Don't let it end this way,Captain.
不要就此结束
Under article 184 of your Interstellar Law...
根据星际法例第184条
I'm placing you under arrest.
我要拘捕你
You're charged with assassinating the Chancellor of the High Council.
你被控暗杀我们的总理
He tried to save him.
他在抢救他
They've been arrested.
他们被捕了
Mr Spock,we've got to do something.
史波克 我们要想办法
I assume command of this ship as of 02:30 hours.
太空船自二点半开始由我指挥
Commander Uhura,notify Starfleet headquarters and request instructions.
乌娜 通知总部 寻求对策
We cannot allow them to be taken to Kronos as prisoners.
我们不能让他们进克林冈监狱
Opening fire will not retrieve them, and we must avoid an armed conflict.
开火无补於事 我们不能交战
We will be able to follow the Captain's movements.
我们可追查船长的行踪
How did you achieve this? Time is precious.
怎样追查？时间很宝贵
We must piece together what happened here tonight.
我们要弄清今晚发生的事
According to our data bank, this ship fired those torpedoes.
资料库显示我们发了两次炮
No way! I sympathize,but we need evidence.
没有可能 我同意 但我们需要证据
Please accompany me.
跟我来
And if we cannot piece together what happened? What then,sir?
如果查不出问题所在呢？
In that case,Mr Chekov,it resides in the purview of the diplomats.
那就要由外交官处理了
The Chancellor of the High Council is dead!
总理死了
The result of an unprovoked attack
他受到突击
while he travelled to see you under a flag of truce on a mission of peace!
当时他在执行和平任务途中
Captain Kirk was legally arrested for the crime.
却克船长依法被捕了
He and Dr. McCoy boarded Kronos One of their own free will.
他和麦盖医生登上了卡龙诺斯一号
None of these facts are in dispute. I have ordered an investigation.
这是不争的事实 我己下令调查
In the meantime... In the meantime...
同时… 同时…
we expect the Federation to abide by the articles of Interstellar Law.
我们希望星盟遵守星际法例
Kirk and Dr. McCoy will stand trial for the assassination of Chancellor Gorkon.
却克和麦盖要为暗杀总理受审
Out of the question. Ambassador Sarek,can we get them extradited?
那当然 沙力 我们可引渡他们吗？
Mr President,I share a measure of personal responsibility in this matter,
我对此事有一定责任
but I am obliged to confirm my esteemed colleagues legal interpretation.
但我得确认他们的法律解释
What is the position of the Romulan government?
罗武伦政府持什麽立场？
I must concur with my colleagues.
我同意他们的意见
You can't believe that Kirk assassinated the Chancellor of the High Council.
难道你相信却克会暗杀总理？
Mr President. I don't know what to believe.
主席 我不知应该信什麽
I'm waiting for your answer,sir.
我在等你答覆
This President is not above the law.
我不能凌驾於法律之上
企业号 请回应 收到吗？
We're to report back at once. We can't abandon Kirk and McCoy.
我们要马上回应 我们不能离弃船长他们
400 years ago,on Earth,workers who felt their livelihood threatened
四百年前工人觉得机器有威胁性
flung their wooden shoes called 'sabots' into the machines to stop them.
把凉鞋掉进机器弄停它
Hence the word 'sabotage'.
这就是英文捣乱一词的由来
We experience technical malfunction. All back-up systems inoperative.
现在我们的後备系统坏了
Excellent. I mean... too bad.
太好了 不 真糟糕
Mr President,I have been named chancellor in my father's place.
我继任了父亲总理一职
Madam Chancellor, you have my condolences on your loss.
总理小姐 请接受我的吊慰
I assure you that this shameful deed will not...
我保证那恶行不是…
Let us come to the point. You want this conference to go forward.
既然大家都想继续和谈
I will attend in one week, on one condition.
我会在一周内出席 条件是…
We will not extradite the prisoners, and you will not attempt to rescue them.
我们不会引渡囚犯你不用营救他们
We would consider any such attempt an act of war.
否则等於煽动战争
We hope you'll be our guest here on Earth.
我们希望你来地球作客
After recent events,you will understand if I prefer a neutral site.
经此一役 我决定保持中立
And in the interests of security,let us keep the location secret for now.
为了安全 会面地点要保密
As you wish,Madam Chancellor.
你作主吧
趁我们有能力 快攻击他们
否则会成为他们的奴隶
动武可以占领全球
战争不合时宜
我们身处险境
我宁死也不委曲求全
这不是我父亲的遗愿
Your father was killed for what he wanted.
你父亲是自愿给杀死的
The peace process will go forward.
和谈要继续
Kirk...
却克…
Kirk will pay for my father's death.
却克要为我父亲偿命
Kirk...
却克…
It's a damn show trial.
不知所谓的审讯
The Enterprise fired on Kronos One without provocation.
企业号突击卡龙诺斯一号
The Chancellor and his advisors...
总理及顾问
having been lulled into a false sense of security
当晚七点半获邀请
by an invitation to a dinner aboard Captain Kirk's vessel
到企业号用膳
at precisely 19:30 hours that same evening.
因此放松了警惕
Call your first witness.
传第一证人
After the first shot we lost our gravitational field.
第一击後 我们失去了引力
I was weightless and couldn't function.
我失控地飘起来
Then two Starfleet crewmen came towards me.
两名星际舰队队员走过来
Or perhaps they merely wore Starfleet uniforms.
可能他们乔装成队员
That remark is speculative. I move that it be stricken.
这只是猜测
We're interested in facts,not theories.
我们想听事实而非理论
If the gravitational unit was not functioning,how could they walk?
没有引力 他们如何行走？
They appeared to be wearing magnetic boots.
他们穿了磁靴
Gravity boots...? Dr. McCoy.
引力靴？麦盖医生
Would you be so good as to tell me
可否告诉我
what is your current medical status?
你目前的健康状况？
Aside from a touch of arthritis, I'd say pretty good.
除了动脉炎外 一切正常
You have a singular wit,Doctor.
你真有幽默感
For 27 years I've been surgeon aboard the U.S.S. Enterprise.
我为企业号服务了二十七年
In three months I stand down.
还有叁个月就退休
You know...
你知道吗？
I believe that you consumed rather a generous amount of Romulan ale
我知道你当晚与众人…
in the officers mess on the night in question.
喝了很多麦芽酒 对吗？
Objection. Sustained.
反对反对有效
We all did. All of us. That doesn't mean...
我们全都喝了 这不表示…
Was Chancellor Gorkon alive when you first examined him?
你诊断高冈总理时他还生存吗？
Barely.
他己奄奄一息
Now be careful,Doctor. Have you ever in your past
你以前试过救活…
saved patients as barely alive as he?
与他一样垂危的病人吗？
I didn't have the medical knowledge I needed for Klingon anatomy.
我不熟识克林冈人的构造
I see. You where there.
是吗？你也在场
You say you are due for retirement. May I ask,do your hands shake?
你快退休了 会手震吗？
Objection! I was nervous.
反对 我很紧张
No. You were incompetent.
不 是你无能
You were incompetent!
你无能
Whether deliberately or as a result of age combined with drink.
蓄意谋杀还是年老加酒精影响
The court will have to determine. My God,man. I tried to save him!
法庭会判决 天 我在救他
I tried to save him.
我尝试救他
I was desperate to save him.
我尽力救他
He was the last best hope in the Universe for peace.
他是实现宇宙和平的最後希望
The witness is excused.
证人可以退下
There we have it,citizens. We have established the particulars of the crime.
我们己知道案情细节
And now we come to the architect of this tragic affair.
现在要审讯这宗悲剧的主谋
James Tiberius Kirk.
却克船长
What would your favourite author say, Captain?
你最喜爱的作家会说什麽？
'Let us sit upon the ground and tell sad stories of the death of kings.'
坐下诉说己故国王的故事
Tell us your sad story,Kirk.
说出你的故事吧
Tell us that you planned to take revenge for the death of your son.
说出你想怎样为子报仇
That's not true. Objection!
不是这样的反对
Captain Kirk has not been identified as the assassin.
没有证据显示却克船长是刺客
I offer into the record this excerpt from the Captain's personal log.
请听听船长这番话
I've never trusted Klingons, and I never will.
我从不信任克林冈人
I've never been able to forgive them for the death of my boy.
他们害死我儿子 不能原谅
再放一次…
I've never trusted Klingons, and I never will.
我从不信任克林冈人
I've never been able to forgive them for the death of my boy.
他们害死我儿子 不能原谅
Are those your words?
这是你的话吗？
Those words were spoken by me.
是我说的
Objection! My client's political views are not on trial.
反对 政治立场与本案无关
On the contrary. Captain Kirk's views are at the very heart of the matter.
他的政治立场正是关键问题
His record shows him to be an insubordinate,unprincipled opportunist
记录显示他是个不守纪律
with a history of violating the chain of command whenever it suited him.
经常违抗命令的人
Continue.
继绩
The record shows that Captain Kirk once held the rank of Admiral
却克船长曾任上将
and he was broken for taking matters into his own hands.
因胡作非为被降职
Do you deny being demoted for these charges. Answer me now!
难道你敢否认吗？回答我
I cannot deny it. You were demoted?
我不能否认 你被降职？
For insubordination? On occasion,I have disobeyed orders.
因违抗命令？我有时不守纪律
Were you obeying or disobeying orders
你策划暗杀高冈总理时
when you arranged the assassination of Chancellor Gorkon?
是奉命行事还是违抗命令？
I didn't know about it until we boarded the ship.
我上了船才知道他遇袭
You still deny the Enterprise fired on Kronos One?
你仍然否认企业号向卡龙诺斯一号开火？
And you still deny your men beamed aboard and shot the Chancellor?
你仍否认派人上船射杀总理？
I cannot confirm or deny actions which I didn't witness.
我不能承认或否认不知情的事
Are you aware that as the captain of a ship,
你身为太空船船长
you are responsible for the actions of your men?
要为下属的行为负贵
I am.
我知道
If it's proved that members of your crew carried out the assassination...
若你的下属证实策划暗杀
They're setting us up. Your Honours! Do not answer.
他们在诬陷你 别回答
Captain Kirk, you will answer the question.
却克船长必须回答
As Captain...
身为船长…
I'm responsible for the crew under my command.
我必须为下属的行为负贵
Your Honours,the state rests.
群情平静了
Send to Commander Enterprise.
发讯给企业号
'We stand ready to assist you. Captain Sulu,U.S.S. Excelsior.'
上进号船长苏路愿意相助
It is the determination of this court that the prisoners are guilty as charged.
法庭裁定被告罪名成立
I wish to note for the record that all the evidence is circumstantial.
本案证据并不充分
I beg the court to consider this when pronouncing its sentence.
恳请法庭判刑前考虑清楚
So noted.
现在宣布
Captain James T. Kirk, Dr. Leonard McCoy.
为了保持和谈的友好气氛
In the interest of fostering amity
却克船长和麦盖医生
for the forthcoming peace talks, the sentence of death is commuted.
法庭决定判你们死刑
It is the judgement of this court
这是法庭的裁决
that,without possibility of reprieve or parole,
没有缓刑 不能假释
you be taken from this place to the dilithium mines
你们要被放逐到劳改星球
on the penal asteroid of Rura Penthe.
鲁拉宾迪的矿场
There to spend the rest of your natural lives.
在那里度过残生
Rura Penthe!
鲁拉宾迪
Known throughout the galaxy as the alien's graveyard.
银河系中的外星人坟墓
Better to kill them now and get it over with.
杀了他更好 一了百了
Lieutenant. The torpedo hit once again,please.
请重播发炮镜头
Hold.
停
It is Enterprise. We fired.
这是企业号 是我们发炮
That is not possible! All weapons visually accounted for,sir.
不可能 全部炮弹还在
An ancestor of mine maintained
我的祖先说过
that if you eliminate the impossible, whatever remains must be the truth.
减去不可能 剩下的就是真理
What does that mean?
什麽意思？
That if we cannot have fired those torpedoes,someone else did.
我们没有发炮 但其他人有
They didn't fire on themselves and there are no other ships present.
他们不会向自己开火当时又无其他船
There was a neutron surge. Not from us.
中子曾经激增不是我们发出的
A neutron surge that big could only be produced by another ship.
促由另一艘船发出
Kronos One? Too far away.
卡龙诺斯一号？太远了
Very near us. Possibly beneath us.
很接近我们 可能在我们下面
If there were a ship beneath us, the Klingons would have seen it.
如果下面有船 他们定会看见
Would they?
会吗？
A Bird of Prey? A Bird of Prey.
猛禽号？猛禽号
Cloaked? They can't fire when they're cloaked.
隐了形？隐形怎能开火
All things being equal,I would agree.
正常情况下是不可能
However,things are not equal. This one can.
但此事很不寻常 或许有可能
We must inform Starfleet Command. Of what?
我们要通知司令 通知什麽？
A new weapon that's invisible? They'll call us raving lunatics.
有新隐形武器？他们一定说我们疯了
They'll say we'll say anything to exonerate the Captain.
说我们为了救船长什麽也敢说
And they would be correct. We have no evidence.
他们说得对 我们没有证据
Only a theory which happens to fit the facts.
只有切合现实的理论
Assuming you're right. Why would they fire on their own President?
他们为何要杀自己的总理？
Indeed.
真是
This ship will be searched from bow to stern.
要彻底搜索这艘船
I do not understand. If there was a ship underneath us
我不明白 如果有船在下面
surely the assassins beamed aboard from that vessel,not Enterprise.
炮弹不会从这里发出
You're forgetting something, Mr Chekov.
你忘了一件事
According to our data banks, this ship fired those torpedoes.
资料库显示我们发了炮
If we did,the killers are here.
凶手应该在这里
If we did not, whoever altered the data banks is here.
改动资料库的人也在这里
In either case, what we are looking for is here.
我们要在此搜寻
What are we looking for,sir? Lieutenant.
搜寻什麽？你认为呢？
Two pairs of gravity boots.
两双引力靴
This is the gulag Rura Penthe.
这里就是劳改星球鲁拉宾迪
There is no stockades,no guard tower,no electronic frontier.
没有监狱  守卫塔  电子边界
Only a magnetic shield prevents beaming.
只有磁力罩
Punishment means exile from prison to the surface.
若有犯错 刑罚是逐上地面
On the surface,nothing can survive.
没有人能在地面生存
Work well,and you will be treated well.
做好点 待遇会好点
Work badly,and you will die.
做得不好 就会死
Oh,my God!
天
The universal translator has been confiscated.
我们没有翻译员
I'm sorry...?
什麽？
He's definitely on about something,Jim.
他有话想说
If this is your spot,we'll move on.
如果这是你的范围 我们会走
He wants your obedience to the Brotherhood of Aliens.
他要你服从外星人公会
He's got it. And your coat.
没问题交出你的外套
I'm afraid not. It wouldn't fit.
恐怕不称身
Thanks. This will help keep you warm.
谢谢 这有助你保暖
I'm Martia. You're Kirk and McCoy. How did you know that?
我是马蒂亚 我知你们是谁 你怎知道？
We don't get many presidential assassins.
你们暗杀总理
We didn't kill Gorkon. Of course not.
我们没有杀高冈 当然没有
But there's a reward for your death. That figures.
但判你死刑有奖赏 有道理
We've been set up.
我们被诬陷
Somebody up there wants you out of the way.
有人不想你们碍事
Any progress? None.
有何进展？没有
A crew of 300 are looking everywhere,but the killers may still be among them.
有叁百人展开搜索但凶手也可能在其中
Surely they have disposed of these boots by now.
磁靴肯定己丢掉了
Would it not have been logical to leave them on Gorkon's ship?
靴子会否留在高冈的船上
Logic must give way to physics. Gravity wasn't restored when they escaped.
他们离开时引力还未恢复
Without the boots,they would have floated off the transporter pads.
没有磁靴就会浮起
Why not simply vaporize them?
何不直接把它化掉？
Like this?
这样？
As you know,no one can fire an unauthorized phaser aboard a starship.
不能未经许可在船上开死光枪
Suppose,when they returned,they threw the boots into the refuse.
可能他们回来时扔掉靴子
I'm having the refuse searched.
我正搜寻垃圾堆
If I'm correct,those boots will cling to the killer's necks like Tiberian bats.
我猜凶手把靴挂在颈上
They couldn't escape without them nor throw them out the window.
他们不能不穿靴离去也不能抛出窗外
Those boots are here. Somewhere.
靴子一定在这里某处
Did someone fire off a phaser? It's alright. It's nothing.
有人开枪吗？没事
Mr Spock,Starfleet is screaming for us to return to port.
星际舰队催促我们回码头
Who fired the... Ah,Mr Scott.
谁发射…史葛
I hear you have difficulty with the warp drive. How long do you need for repair?
听说船索坏了 要修理多久？
There's nothing wrong with the bloody thing.
船索那有问题？
If we return to space dock,the killers can dispose of their footwear
若我们回去 凶手会丢掉靴子
and we will never see the Captain or Dr. McCoy alive again.
我们无缘再见船长和麦盖了
It could take weeks. Thank you.
需要几星期 谢谢
Val'eris,inform Starfleet our warp drive is inoperative.
通知舰队我们的船索失灵
A lie? An error.
这是谎话？只是差错
We have lost all contact with the Captain and Dr. McCoy.
我们跟船长和麦盖完全失去联络
Yes,at the moment they're surrounded by a magnetic shield.
现在他们被磁罩包围
But if I know the Captain,he is deep into planning his escape.
我猜船长一定在计划逃狱
You've got him where you want him,Jim!
却克 你触怒了他
Are you alright? I think so.
你没事吧？没事
They'll respect you now. I was lucky that thing had knees.
你现在受到尊重了 幸好那东西有膝盖
That was not his knee.
那不是他的膝盖
Not everybody keep their genitals in the same place,Captain.
每个人的生殖部位都不一样
Anything you want to tell me?
你是说…
See what you can do for him. Let him know we're not holding a grudge.
快去解释我们无意冒犯
Suppose he's holding a grudge?
他可能很生气
When whoever it is makes their move,you won't be here to ask if he's the one.
不论人们做什麽 也不要多问
Do you want to get out of here? There's got to be a way.
你想逃出去吗？一定有出路的
Three months before retirement. What a way to finish.
退休前叁个月就完蛋了
We're not finished. Speak for yourself.
我们还未完蛋 你自圆其说
One day,one night... Kobayashi Maru!
迟早会完的
Bones! Are you afraid of the future?
你害怕将来吗？
I believe that was the general idea that I was trying to convey.
这正是我一直想说的事
I don't mean this future. What is this multiple choice?
我不是指这个将来 是什麽？选择题？
Some people are afraid... of what might happen.
有些人害怕将会发生的事
I was terrified. What terrified you,specifically?
我很怕你怕什麽？
No more Neutral Zone.
再没有中立区
I was used to hating Klingons.
我一向憎恨克林冈人
It never even occurred to me to take Gorkon at his word.
我从不信高冈所言
Spock was right. We all felt exactly the same.
史波克 对了 别自贵 我们同样难受
No. Somebody felt a lot worse.
不 有人难受得多
I'm beginning to understand why.
我开始明白了
If you've got any bright ideas,now is the time.
若你没有好主意现在是时候…
Time is the problem. You and I are nothing.
时间是问题 我们帮不上忙
You heard the judge the peace conference is on again.
你听到吗？和谈恢复了
Whoever killed Gorkon is bound to attempt another assassination.
杀高冈的凶手会再进行暗杀
Unless we can get out of here.
除非我们逃离这里
It's me Martia. Listen. No one has ever escaped from Rura Penthe.
是我 没有人曾成功逃狱
Except us. It is possible.
除了我们 有可能的
I know how to get outside the shield.
我知道如何逃出罩外
How do we fit in? Getting outside the shield is easy.
我们要怎样做？出去其实很容易
After that,you have to get us off the surface before we freeze. Can you?
但要在冻僵前逃出生天
It's possible. I can't make it alone.
没问题 我需要你帮忙
You're the likeliest candidate to come here for months.
你是最有潜质的候选人
Candidate for what?
什麽候选人？
Go to lift 7 in the morning for mining duty. I'll see you there.
早上采矿时在7号电梯见
Don't disappoint me.
别令我失望
What is it with you,anyway? Still think we're finished?
你怎麽了？还认为我们会完蛋吗
More than ever.
从未如此担心过
Sorry to wake you,sir.
吵醒你真对不起
Starfleet requests any data we have on the whereabouts of Enterprise.
星际舰队想知道企业号的位置
What?
什麽？
They're refusing to acknowledge signal to return to space dock,sir.
他们拒绝确认回码头的信号
Signal Starfleet that we have no idea location Enterprise.
回覆说我们不知企业号的位置
Sir? You have hearing problems?
船长？你听觉有问题吗？
No,sir.
没有
Klingon blood.
克林冈人的血
They must have walked through it when it was floating and tracked it back here.
肯定是他们把血迹踩了进来
This is the first evidence which corroborates our theory.
这是我们的第一证据
Now we go to Starfleet?
要通知星际舰队吗？
We expand our search to include uniforms.
现在连制服也要搜查
All uniforms?
所有制服？
Clear,sir. Make a hole.
这里没有
Coming through. Coming through.
请让开
Sir! Sir!
船长…
I think we've been had. No,you weren't,Doctor.
她欺骗我们 你没有被骗
Get off at the first level. Follow the gang into the mine.
在第一层离去 跟大队到矿场
They don't take girls.
他们不载女孩
You are crewman Dax? Yes. What is the problem?
你是迪斯？对 什麽事
Perhaps you know the Russian epic of Cinderella?
听过灰姑娘的故事吗？
If shoe fits wear it.
试试是否合穿
Mr Chekov...
查哥夫…
Watch me.
看我的
What kind of creature is this? Last night you two were...
这是什麽生物？昨晚你们… 别提了
Get in.
进来
Come on. We don't have a lot of time.
快 我们时间无多
Hurry!
快点
Up there.
上面
Come on climb!
来 爬上来
Here,you'll need these. Quickly!
穿上这些 快
Stay close.
跟我来
There they are. They emerge from the beaming shield.
他们在这里 他们快逃出来了
Mr Scott,start your engines. Mr Chekov,set course for Rura Penthe.
史葛 开动引擎查哥夫 驶往鲁拉宾迪
Mr Spock,Rura Penthe is deep inside the Klingon frontier.
鲁拉宾迪在克林冈边境内深处
If we're discovered... Correct.
若我们发现… 对
We need a feat of linguistic legerdemain and intrepidity
在船长和麦盖冻死前
before the Captain and Dr. McCoy freeze to death.
我们要运用掩眼法和勇气
Leave me,I'm finished. No!
别理我 我完了 不会的
Bones,I'm wearing a viridium patch on my back.
我身上有追踪器
Spock slapped it there before we went on Gorkon's ship.
史波克 在我们上船前贴上
That cunning little Vulcan.
这个狡猾的维冈人
Come on! We're in the clear.
来 我们安全了
Now that we're outside the shield,they can locate us two sectors away.
我们在罩外他们可追踪到我们
If they're even looking for us.
如果他们在找我们的话
这是莫斯卡短波电台
这是什麽船？
We must respond. A universal translator would be recognised.
我们要回应 需要翻译
我们是你的货船厄斯华
离开了卡龙诺斯
六星期
'What is your destination,over? '
你们往什麽目的地？
我们有食物
物资供应
别捉虫子
Would you mind explaining that little trick you do?
可否解释一下你的把戏？
I'm a Chameloid. I've heard about you.
我是金密莱人 我听过这名字
Shape-shifters. I thought you were mythical.
变形人 真神奇
Give a girl a chance,Captain.
船长 给女孩一个机会
It takes a lot of effort.
很费劲的
I don't doubt it.
我同意
Stop me if I'm wrong,
如果我错了 请告诉我
but do we have any way of knowing whether this is the real you?
那一个才是真正的你？
I thought I would assume a pleasing shape.
我采用了吸引人的形象
We're outside the shield. Now it's your turn,Captain.
我们己逃脱 到你了
If you say so.
这个…
Are you crazy? !
你疯了吗？
She didn't need our help. Where did you get these convenient clothes?
她不需我们帮助你的便服从何来的？
Don't tell me that flare is standard prison issue.
那火光不是监中物件
It's to let them know where we are. Ask her what she's getting in return.
她在通风报信 换取报酬
A full pardon... which doesn't cover this.
你竟然这样对我
An accident wasn't good enough. Come on,Spock.
这不可能是意外
Good enough for one. Two would have looked suspicious.
次意外没有问题 两次会惹人怀疑
Killed while attempting escape. That's convincing for both.
逃亡时被杀 双方也可信
Surprise!
意外吧
Your friends are late. They'll be along.
你的朋友来迟了 他们正赶来
I can't believe I kissed you. Must have been your lifelong ambition.
我竟然吻过你 你一定期待己久
Isn't it time you became something else?
你是时候改变形象了
I like it here.
我喜欢这个形象
Well,well,well...
好了…
What took you so long?
你为何来得这麽晚？
Kill him,he's the one.
杀了他 他才是真身
Not me,you idiot him!
不是我 是他
No witnesses. Killed while trying to escape.
没有证人逃亡时被杀
Damned clever,if you ask me. It's a classic.
真聪明这是经典
That's what he wanted. Who? Who wanted us killed?
这是他们的意思 谁？谁想杀我们？
Since you're all going to die anyway,why not tell you?
反正你要死 告诉你又何妨
His name is...
他是…
Damn it! What the hell! Son of a...! Couldn't you have waited two seconds?
真讨厌…你为何不多等两秒？
He was about to explain the whole thing.
他正交代事情始末
You want to go back? Absolutely not!
你想回去？绝对不
This is the bridge. We're still in Klingon space.
这是驾驶台 我们仍在克林冈领空
Deck 9,remain at battle stations. Deck 9,remain at battle stations.
9号甲板 维持战斗岗位
他们被接回星盟太空船
我可以追踪…
逃脱
却克不知道和谈的场地
你肯定？
你愿意冒险吗？
舵手 快去拦截企业号
The Klingons have a Bird of Prey that can fire while cloaked.
克林冈人有艘猛禽号可以隐形发炮
She torpedoed Gorkon's ship. So that's it.
它向高冈的船发炮 就是它
We believe that Gorkon's murderers are aboard this ship.
凶手就在这艘船上
Has the peace conference begun? Who knows? The location is secret.
和谈开始了没有？不知道 地点保密
There's always something. Captain! Mr Spock!
一定有事船长 史波克
I found the uniforms with the Klingon blood on them.
我发现染有克林冈人血迹的制服
But the uniforms belong to these two men. Burke and Samno.
制服属於这两个人卜奇和沉努
Not anymore. Phaser on 'stun' at close range.
有人近距离向他们开枪
First rule of assassination kill the assassins.
暗杀规例第一条:杀死刺客
Now we're back to square one. Can I talk to you?
我们退回起点了 我想和你谈谈
Why weren't they vaporized? It would set off the alarm.
他们为何没有化掉 会惊动警钟
It's possible.
这也可行
Now hear this. Now hear this.
请注意…
Court reporter to sick bay. Code blue urgent.
速记员请到病房 蓝色急事
Statements to be taken at once from Yeomen Burke and Samno.
急需录取卜奇和沉努的口供
Repeat,court reporter to sick bay. Code blue urgent.
速记员请到病房 蓝色急事
Statements to be taken.
要录取口供
Repeat,statements to be taken from Yeomen Burke and Samno.
录取卜奇和沉努的口供
You have to shoot.
你应该开枪
If you are logical,you have to shoot.
你有逻辑的话 就应该开枪
I do not want to. What you want is irrelevant.
我不想的 你的目的毫无意义
What you've chosen is at hand.
你的选择已经得到
I'd just as soon you didn't.
我不希望是你
The operation is over.
手术完了
I did not fire. You cannot prove anything.
我没有发炮 你没有证据
Yes,I can. At my trial my personal log was used against me.
审讯时 我的日志成为证物
How long did you wait outside my quarters before I noticed you?
你一直在我房外探听
You knew?
你知道？
I tried to tell you,but you would not listen.
我想告诉你 但你不听
Neither of us was hearing very well that night.
当晚没有人留心听
There were things I tried to tell you,about having faith.
我曾叫你要有信心
You have betrayed the Federation. All of you.
你们全部也背叛了星盟
And what have you've been doing? Saving Starfleet.
你认为自己在做什麽 拯救星际舰队
Klingons cannot be trusted. Sir... You said so yourself.
克林冈人不可靠船长 你说过的
They killed your son. Did you not wish Gorkon dead?
他们杀了你的儿子你不想高冈死吗？
'Let them die',you said. Did I misinterpret you?
你说过 让他们自生自灭
And you were right.
你说对了
They conspired with us to assassinate their own Chancellor.
他们与我们串通暗杀自己的总理
How trustworthy can they be?
他们怎会可信？
Klingons and Federation members conspiring together.
克林冈人与星盟成员串通
Who is 'us'? All who stands to lose from peace.
谁是[我们]？不爱和平的人
Names,Lieutenant.
说出他们的名字
My comrades will make certain all your transmissions are jammed.
我的同党会干扰你们的通讯
Names,Lieutenant! I do not remember.
说出他们的名字 我记不起
A lie?
这是谎话？
A choice.
只是选择
Spock.
史波克
Admiral Cartwright.
卡上将
From Starfleet?
来自星际舰队？
Who else?
还有谁？
General... Chang.
张上将
Who else? Romulan Ambassador and others.
还有呢？罗武伦大使及其他人
Where is the peace conference?
和谈在哪里举行？
She does not know.
她不知道
Then we're dead.
那我们死了
I have been dead before. Contact Excelsior.
我己死过一次 联络上进号
She'll have the co-ordinates. I've already got it,sir.
他们会提供合作 我己联络了他
Standing by,Captain Kirk. Sulu.
却克船长 准备 苏路
You realize that by even talking to us,you're violating regulations.
你知否我们通话是违反规条？
I'm sorry,Captain. Your message is breaking up.
对不起 我听不清楚
Bless you,Sulu. Where is the peace conference?
和谈在哪里举行？
They'll attempt another assassination.
他们会发动第二次暗杀
It's at Camp Khitomer,near the Romulan border.
杰图马营 罗武伦边境附近
I'm sending the co-ordinates on a coded frequency.
我会用密码信号发给你
We'll need more than that.
恐怕这还不够
There's a Bird of Prey on the look-out for us that can fire while cloaked.
我们被猛禽号监视它可以隐形发炮
Surely not.
不是吧
How many of those things are there? Come on,Lieutenant.
有多少人在那里？
Just the prototype. Do you hear that?
只有样本你听到吗？
I'm getting under way now. We're in Alpha Quadrant.
我现在起航 但我们郧脍一区
The chances of our reaching the conference in time are slim.
恐怕赶不及到会场
When does this conference start? According to my information today.
会议何时开始？我收到的资料是今天
Thank you,Captain Sulu. Don't mention it,Captain Kirk.
谢谢你 别客气
Spock?
史波克 ？
I prefer it dark.
不要开灯
Dining on ashes? You were right.
你在忏悔？对
It was arrogant presumption on my part that got us into this situation.
都怪我自视过高
You and the Doctor might have been killed.
你和麦盖差点没命
The night is young.
我们经验不够
You said it yourself,it was logical. Peace is worth a few personal risks.
你说为了和平 值得犯险
You're a great one for logic.
你有逻辑头脑
I'm a great one for rushing in where angels fear to tread.
我则好管闲事
We're both extremists. Reality is probably somewhere in between.
我们太激进 该学习中庸之道
I couldn't get past the death of my son.
我不能忘掉丧子之痛
I was prejudiced by her accomplishments as a Vulcan.
她的出色表现令我偏爱
Gorkon had to die before I understood how prejudiced I was.
高冈死了我才知道自己十分偏激
Is it possible...
是不是…
that we two,you and I,have grown so old and inflexible
我们又老又不灵活
that we have outlived our usefulness?
什麽也做不来了？
Would that constitute a joke?
这是不是笑话？
It wasn't your fault. I was responsible.
这不是你的错 我有责任
For no actions but your own. That's not what you said at your trial.
只需为自己的行为负责 你在庭上不是这样说
That was as captain of the ship. Human beings...
身为船长 作为人…
We both know that I am not human.
你该知道我不是人
Do you want to know something? Everybody's human.
你知道吗？众生也是人
I find that remark... insulting.
我觉得这句话很侮辱
Come,I need you.
来 我需要你
Madam Chancellor,members of the diplomatic corps...
总理小姐 各位外交人员
honoured guests.
各位来宾
The United Federation of Planets welcomes you to Camp Khitomer.
星盟欢迎你们来到杰图马营
She's out here somewhere.
猛禽号一定在附近
But if she's cloaked... Then all we have is a radiation surge.
如果它隐了形 唯有看辐射读数
By the time we're close enough to record it,we're ashes.
我们录得辐射时 已经炸死了
2.06
2.06…
2.03
2.03…
Close enough to beam down? Not yet. In two minutes. 1.58.
可以起程了吗？还有两分钟 1.58
Go to impulse power for Khitomer.
全速驶往杰图马营
Let us redefine progress to mean that just because we can do a thing
我们有能力做一件事
it does not necessarily follow that we must do that thing.
不代表我们一定要去做
Uhura? Nothing,Captain.
邬娜？没有异像
If she's here,she's rigged for silent running.
猛禽号可能正在无声航行
Coming up on transporter range in 57 seconds.
还有57秒到达运送器范围
Transporter room. Stand by to beam down.
运送器房 准备
53...
53秒
48 seconds.
48秒
44...
44秒
I can see you,Kirk.
却克 我看到你了
Chang.
张上将
Can you see me?
你看到我吗？
Now be honest,Captain. Warrior to warrior.
老实说 战士对战士
You do prefer it this way,don't you? As it was meant to be.
你喜欢这样的 是吗？
No peace in our time.
我们这里没有和平
'Once more unto the breach,dear friends.'
好朋友 进攻又开始了
This is fun. Reverse engines. All astern.
真有趣 回动引擎 退後
One and a half impulse power. Back off!
以1.5冲力退後
它做什麽？
What's she waiting for?
它在等什麽？
Probably attempting to ascertain why we are reversing.
可能想知道我们为何退後
Wondering whether we detect her.
看我们是否侦察到它
Incoming!
来了
In range? Not yet,sir.
相通了吗？还未
Come on!
快点
She'll fly apart. Fly her apart,then!
它会爆炸的 那就炸掉它
Many speculated about my father's motives.
很多人也怀疑我父亲的动机
Some said he was an idealist. Others said he had no choice.
有人说他是空想家有人说他没有选择
If Praxis had not exploded,his idealism wouldn't have found expression.
如果普拉西斯不爆炸他不会有此空想
We are a proud race.
我们以自己的民族为荣
We are here because we intend to go on being proud.
我们想继续感到自豪
Go to auxiliary power! Auxiliary circuits destroyed.
启动後备电力 後备电路受到破坏
'Tickle us,do we not laugh? Prick us,do we not bleed? '
痒了可以不笑吗？刺伤了可以不流血吗
'Wrong us,shall we not revenge? '
遭到欺负可以不报复吗？
Gas.
气
Gas,Captain. Under impulse power she expands fuel,like all vessels.
船在冲力下要加气
We call it 'plasma',but it is merely ionised gas.
要离子气
What about our equipment to catalogue gaseous anomalies?
记录气体反常的设备呢？
The thing's got to have a tail-pipe.
那一定有排气管
Doctor,would you assist me in performing surgery on a torpedo?
医生 可否为飞弹做手术？
Fascinating.
好
Hard to starboard.
转右
The proposed agenda is as follows: The evacuation of Kronos
我们建议在地球时间五十年内
has been calculated within the 50 Earth year time span.
撤走我们的居民
Phase 1 preparation for evacuation...
第一阶段:准备撤走…
Captain,she's packing quite a wallop. Shields weakening.
我们受到猛击 防护罩受损
Shields up! Alright,now we're giving them something else to shoot at.
开防护罩 等待他们进攻
The game's afoot.
游戏还未结束
Excelsior's been hit! 'Our revels now are ended',Kirk.
上进号被击中了 游戏结束了
'Cry havoc,and let slip the dogs of war.'
大混乱 我要发动战争
Bones,where's my torpedo? Bet you wished you'd stayed in bed.
我的飞弹呢 不用操心
Shields collapsing!
防护罩塌下了
The key,please. Time is short.
拿钥匙来 时间无多
The hull has been compromised. I wonder how bad.
船身被击中 不知损毁隋况如何？
Connect echo-bars.
接上回波棒
discuss the report on phase 2.
讨论第二阶段的报告
Alter circuit A. Sensor.
更改A电路 探测器
we commence within minutes of the preparation.
开始看计划的议程
'I am constant as the Northern star.' I'd give real money,if he'd shut up.
我像北极星般不败 他闭嘴的话 我给他钱
Plate,please.
拿板来
and assimilation will consume...
同化要花费…
We've got a heart beat.
有反应了
with the Klingon Empire...
克林冈帝国…
Key,please.
钥匙
Where's that torpedo? She's ready.
飞弹呢？准备好了
Lock and load!
准备发射
Fire!
发射
'To be... or not'...
做还是…
'to be.'
不做
Target that explosion and fire.
瞄准它开火
Fire!
发射
This work will occupy us throughout most of the week.
这项工作需时一星期
I hope that the delegation
希望代表团
can implement the provisions of Phase 1 by the first of next month.
下月前履行第一阶段的规定
As you know,time is of the essence.
时间是关键
Out of the way!
让开
Mr President!
主席
Kirk,Enterprise.
我是企业号的却克
保护总理
Arrest those men! Arrest yourself!
拘捕他们 拘捕你自己
We've got a full confession.
她己彻底招供
This is not Klingon blood. Cartwright. Just a minute.
这不是克林冈人的血 卡上将 别逃
What's happened? What's the mean of all of this?
什麽事？这是怎麽一回事？
It's about the future,Madam Chancellor.
有关未来的事
Some people think the future means the end of history.
有人认为未来代表历史的终结
We haven't run out of history quite yet.
但历史还未完结
Your father called the future...
你的父亲称未来为…
'the undiscovered country'.
尚未发现的地方
People can be very frightened of change.
人人都害怕转变
You've restored my father's faith.
你重建了我父亲的信心
And you've restored my son's.
你重建了我儿子的信心
Once again,we've saved civilization as we know it.
我们再一次挽救了文明
And they're not going to prosecute.
幸好他们不起诉我们
They could have prosecuted me. I felt like Val'eris.
我或会像韦利丽一样遭起诉
They don't arrest people for having feelings.
不会的
And it's a good thing,too. If they did,we'd all have to turn ourselves in.
真好 否则我们会有麻烦
Captain Kirk. Captain Sulu.
切克船长 苏路船长
As much to the crew of the Enterprise,I owe you my thanks.
我代表所有船员向你致谢
Nice to see you in action one more time,Captain Kirk. Take care.
很高兴再次与你合作 保重
My God,that's a big ship. Not so big as her captain.
天 真是艘大船 但也不及船长伟大
So... This is goodbye?
这是再见了？
It's about time we got underway ourselves.
我们是时候各自启航
Captain,I have orders from Starfleet Command.
星际舰队有令
We're to put back to space dock immediately... to be decommissioned.
马上返回太空码头 解散队伍
If I were human,I believe my response would be:
如果我是人 我的反应会是…
'Go to hell.'
去死吧
If I were human.
如果我是人的话
Course heading,Captain?
要驶向哪里？
Second star to the right.
右面第二个星球
And straight on 'til morning.
直驶至明早
Captain's log,stardate 9529.1.
掏吕长日志 星历9529.1
This is the final cruise of the Starship Enterprise under my command.
这是企业号最後一次在我指挥下航行
This ship,and her history
这艘船和它的历史
will shortly become the care of another crew.
很快会由另一队伍接管
To them and their posterity will we commit our future.
我们把未来交给後世的人们
They'll continue the voyages we have begun
他们会继续我们的旅程
and journey to all the undiscovered countries
探索所有尚未到过的地方
boldly going where no man,where no one...
勇敢地到没有人…
has gone before.
到过的地方